If you're a personal trainer,
without trying to scare you too much,
I think that
your days are very numbered,
whether you've been in the profession for
10 years or
you're just getting started. You see,
I've been running one of the world's
largest
online personal training apps called JSA
since 2017, and I can see the
trends. I can see the numbers,
the analytics, and better yet,
I can see the threats
in real time. Now,
let me tell you a little story.
For any of you that aren't from the UK,
we have black cabs.
They are taxis that operate around London.
And what people don't realize
is being a black cab driver in London used
to be one
of the most difficult things ever because
you didn't just need to know how to
drive.
You needed to learn something called The
Knowledge.
Now, for The Knowledge,
you had to know 25,000 streets in
London off by heart. So
if someone jumps in and says,
"I need to go there," you
know where it is.
You need to know 20,000 landmarks.
What people didn't realize is
if you ever saw anyone with a moped going
out with a
clipboard driving around London, they
were often studying for The Knowledge,
and it
would take three to four years of study to
become a black cab driver.
MRI scans even showed
that black cab drivers' hippocampus,
which is
a region in the brain,
grew because of this.
And I'm sure any of you, like me,
that use Waze to go everywhere,
if you use Google
Maps, you're mental.
You use Waze because then you can see
where those police
cameras are.
That part of my brain has shrunk because
even when I go home and see
my parents, I know where things are,
but I have to put it into the sat nav
because
that part of my brain's atrophied.
Anyway, everyone was sure
that black cabs would be a part of London
forever and that The Knowledge would be a
thing.
And it was only when Uber came along,
that finished. No one saw it coming.
With Uber, all of
that knowledge just became redundant.
No one cared.
Because an unqualified driver
that didn't know where the hell he
was could then
have a bit of software on their phone
that would tell them where to go, the best
route, and even have all the analytics
and data from current trends in
traffic to know which is the best route.
Now looking back, it makes sense.
Back in the day, we had travel agents.
When you wanted to get your group together
to go to Malia back in '07, you go to a
travel agent, they'd sort it out for you.
Again, websites arrived,
and you could book your travel on there.
You didn't have to go to Thomson on the
high street.
Again, booking your holidays, you thought,
this will never go anywhere.
Blockbuster.
For any of you too young for that,
don't even worry.
And again, let's think about people
that used to process films in cameras.
Up until the point
that these businesses vanished,
everyone thought they'd be
around forever.
So let's look at personal training now.
To me, there are three main threats
which are going to jeopardize personal
training over the next few years,
and this video is about preparing for them
so that you can survive this oncoming
wave.
The first one has to be weight loss
medications.
And even calling them weight loss
medications I don't think is enough here.
We have a GLP-1. We can look at Ozempic,
known as Wegovy at the top.
Then a better one came along known as
Mounjaro, which is tirzepatide.
Now,
you could call Ozempic a single agonist,
Mounjaro a double
agonist. Then retatrutide
is on its way through trials as a triple
agonist.
GLP, GIP,
and the effect it's going to have,
potentially treating
fatty liver disease, obesity.
Andrew Huberman reckons it could be a
trillion-dollar
drug.
The effects of these weight loss
medications are already impacting the
economy in ways that we can see. Aviation.
Planes are using less fuel than they did a
few years ago.
In jewelry, jewelers
are now using less gold in wedding rings.
Obesity rates,
for the first time in history,
have started to decline.
The world is changing because of these
drugs.
Whether you like that or not,
it doesn't matter.
That's the reality of it.
Now,
there is opportunity within this because
there's now a massive cohort of
people that would never have stepped foot
in a gym, that wouldn't care about
coaching, that now
are mindful of muscle wastage,
getting adequate protein,
and preserving muscle tissue.
Those people will find their way into the
fitness
industry.
So whilst weight loss medications could
extinct us, they can also bring
us opportunity, but then again,
that opportunity is only going to be
available
to those that are out there doing the
things that modern businesses need to do
to
get attention.
Standing by reception in the gym
is not going to get
you all of those people on weight loss
medications.
You're going to have to be at the
forefront of social media.
I could make this a whole video
altogether. That's the first threat.
Now, the second one, again, people
that know more about AI
are probably going to
step in here. I think apps
are going to die a death in the next few
years,
especially coaching apps, fitness apps.
Again,
I have one of the biggest apps ever,
and I think we're going to see AI
agents that pretty much are on our phone.
And rather than even opening an app,
you just talk to your agent.
"Oh, yeah,
I'm on my way to the gym." "How you
feeling?" "Yeah, a little bit sore."
"In the last session, you did this.
How did you feel at the end of it?" "Yeah,
you know what?
It's about an 8 out of 10 difficulty."
You'll just be able to talk to your agent
about everything.
"How'd you sleep last night?" "Yeah,
I actually slept pretty
good." But the agent's also going to have
the data from your Eight Sleep mattress.
Your agent could also have some input into
the amount of work you've been doing,
how stressed you are,
your resting heart rate,
all of these different metrics.
And your AI agent is going to say, "Hey,
I've derived you a workout for today.
It could seem like there's less here than
usual, but because of your heart rate
variability,
the amount you slept last night,
and how much work you did yesterday,
we think for you to optimize
and get the most out of the session,
you're going to
do this much." The idea of going outside
of your AI agent to hire a personal
trainer, I think could seem stupid.
I think that your AI agent as well
is going to say, "Hey, James.
I know that you've got 45 seconds
remaining on this set.
Do you want me to top up your protein
order?
Because we've seen that
if you've had one protein scoop a day,
that you've only got
two scoops left and the shipping
is three days.
Do you want me to go ahead and order
that for you?" "Yeah. Do you know what?
I'd love you to do that." Then just as
you're leaving the gym, "Hey, James.
Your Porsche is due for a service in the
next seven days.
Considering it's Friday,
probably one of the best times to get
through to the
Porsche Service Center.
Do you want us to call ahead and book
that in for you?"
"Yeah, please. Thanks." I think
that we're going to have AI agents
that take care
of everything for us. "Hey,
I need to go to Dubai on these dates.
Can you organize all my travel?" "Sure.
Would you like a window or aisle seat,
James?" Now, I could be completely wrong
with this.
This three-year buffer could be six,
could be 10, could be one.
But let me ask you this. Even
if this seems like an extinction-level
event, you can
either be ready for it,
or it's just going to fucking slap you
and destroy you when
it comes along. And for me, I think
that we should aim for this catastrophe to
happen so we can maximize what we do in
the next three years.
The third threat, I think,
is just going to be exhaustion.
So in advertising, when we create adverts,
you can only show them to people a set
amount of time before people get exhausted
of it and don't want to see it anymore.
Now, since the pandemic,
every single coach is an online coach.
Every single person
is now an online business coach doing what
I'm doing.
But funnily enough,
a lot of my competitors never even ran
competitive fitness
businesses.
There's even one woman I'm working with at
the moment, and she's like,
"Oh, I joined this guy's program."
And I look at his page and I'm like, why?
Charging her 15 grand.
The guy's not even got 10,000 followers,
and he's teaching
you how to build a social media platform.
He's never even had a big business,
and he's the guy that's going to grow your
business to the next scale.
I didn't get that.
I was like, out of all people, why him?
So yeah, I reckon you have three years.
So if you're just newly qualified or
if you're a seasoned vet,
[chuckles] this next
three-year window is where everything
happens.
But there's good news in the back of this.
It's not like it's going to be three
years, then you're fucked
and you're out on
the street and you're homeless. It's
that in the next three years, there
is so much
work you need to do that you can adapt
and pivot and react to what's coming.
Now, quickly, in the description, there
is my PT Starter Kit.
It's $99 US, which isn't a lot.
And you get my Short-Form Content Mastery,
which
teaches you everything about making
content.
But then also there
is a personal trainer course in there
about running and
operating a business in person
and going online.
And there's currently $99 off that,
so there's going to be a link for
that in the
description. I'm just going to send
that to the boys.
And you can buy that or don't. It's $99.
I mean, you get one client out of it.
Anyway, back to the video.
So there's three real phases we need to
think about to
deal with these three very real threats.
The first stage is going to be learn,
the second stage is going to be the pivot,
and the third stage
is going to be the redirect,
and we'll get onto this in a
second. So any of you
that watched my videos before will know
that there's a
four-stage system that you need to learn,
not just as a personal trainer, but
running any business. Socials, squeeze,
sell, scale.
Now, the interesting thing here
is the socials element.
I learned how to operate social media as a
personal trainer.
The personal trainer account,
I got 1.4 million.
But then I could replicate
that onto my business channel,
which has now got 44,000
subscribers,
which means I could then replicate
that to create a platform for my
online coaching app, 96,000 on Instagram.
Which means I could then create a podcast
channel, which has got 46.9
thousand.
Once you learn how to grow a social media
channel, you know how to grow
all social media channels.
It's not like you learn how to grow
socials as a PT,
then suddenly everything else
is so much more difficult. If anything,
the opposite.
Personal trainer account's the hardest to
grow because the least people care about
you buying your fucking workout
Let's have a look at the Nutonic account.
78,500 Instagram subscribers.
And by the way,
if any of you head to nutonic.com
and you buy anything from us and
you don't think it's better than what you
think, just email me, james@nutonic.com,
and I'll refund you.
So once you learn how to crack just one
form of social media,
you actually unlock the keys to doing it
for everything.
So whatever businesses you have,
because you might be an accountant
or a barber or
something else,
once you learn how to grow one account,
you can take those skills
and apply them to everything.
Because let's think about those skills.
Repetition, eating shit.
Let's think about Thomas Edison,
for example.
Thomas Edison,
who invented the light bulb,
you wouldn't be able to see me right
now if he hadn't have invented it,
reportedly tested over 10,000 different
filament materials before actually
inventing the light bulb.
A journalist once asked him about failing
10,000 times, and Thomas
Edison said, "I've not failed.
I have found 10,000 ways that won't work."
And I guarantee for any of you watching
this, if you were to try and find
10,000 reels that didn't work, my God,
you would find a lot that do.
Chris and myself have done about 5,000
Instagram posts.
He's at 3 million, I'm at 1.4,
which means he's kind of winning the
Instagram race,
but I've got a nicer car. But yeah,
it took years and thousands of
opportunities
for Thomas Edison to invent the light
bulb, and I love to remind people,
why do you
think that you're so fucking special
that you're not going to suck like that?
So over the next three years,
you have the opportunity to have as many
free spins
as you want on this roulette game of
social media.
That's what people don't realize.
Every single spin is fucking free,
and the return on investment can be
massive. All it takes
is for one post to boot off
and your whole life has
changed forever.
Do you not understand that?
You've got this little arm,
ching-ding-ding-ding-ding-ding-ding-ding-ding.
Every time you post, you
are rolling the fucking dice to
potentially
not just winning, but learning
and getting feedback from your audience
and getting
feedback from the world. It's one video.
And if you're posting once a day,
even then I'm like, "Is
that fucking it?" I'm
pretty sure Chris Williamson
is posting 14, 15 times a day.
He's outsourced an entire company to do
it, and I'm about to do something similar
because I'm well aware
that I've probably only got three years
left to really
maximize everything from social media.
So I'm going to do the same.
If I have this life from posting less than
once a day, imagine what I'd have if I
posted five times a day.
So that's socials. Then we have squeeze.
Ultimately,
we can't control the algorithms
and how they change, and we saw things
like the TikTokification of social media,
where at the moment, to put it briefly,
people see your content not because they
follow you, they see it because it's good.
And the algorithms work very simply like
this. They get your reel.
They don't go, "Is this good
or not?" They go,
"Let's give it to 100 people and see
how they react." The majority of those 100
people don't fucking follow you.
So when you're making content,
please think to yourself,
"If I showed this to 100
people,
how many would actually like it?" Because
showing it to your audience is
very, very different. Cool. Then
if 100 people quite a lot like it,
let's give it
to 1,000 people. Quite a lot like it.
Go to a million people.
Quite a lot like it.
Until you get the diminishing point of
returns, or there's no longer a captive
audience that speak English. Cool.
Now, off the back of that,
we need to get as much data as we can,
because at the
moment,
if you were to delete my Instagram
or this YouTube, I've still got
thousands of people that I can email.
Case in point, this morning,
I actually looked at our revenue for the
month, and it
was a bit slow.
So I've decided I'm going to dial up the
amount of production
videos that I'm making for the channel.
But also, I thought,
what offer could I put out there to get
money in my bank
account in the next 48 hours?
I could run a discount on my mentorship
or whatever.
Then I thought, actually,
why not get my PT starter kit going out
there?
Because that has really helped a lot of
personal trainers.
And I could be real with them because I
actually sat at my desk this morning
thinking, "Fuck,
I've probably only got three years left."
And while sitting there
thinking about how I'm going to maximize
the next three years, I thought, "Fuck,
this is a good video." So I get in my car,
come here, and make it for you.
So you've got the socials.
You've got the squeeze to get as much data
as you can
over the next three years because all
those people that do coaching with you,
next
minute, they're buying your fucking drink.
When I look at the analytics from my daily
emails that go out to people, about half
the people go to my coaching app,
half the people go to Nutonic.
Then yesterday's email,
a third went to Nutonic,
a third went to my coaching app,
and a third went to my podcast. You see,
even growing the podcast is a
diversification of all the things I
learned from being a personal trainer.
So the next stage would be sell,
and you learn a lot about selling.
So at this point,
I'm pretty much an expert in social media,
as you can see.
1.1 million Facebook, 1.8 million TikTok,
1.4 million
Instagram, nearly 500K on one YouTube,
50K on the other YouTube, 50K on the other
YouTube.
Podcast coming up to 20 million downloads.
The socials element,
I've done a lot of it.
Squeeze, got over half a
million emails. Then the sell.
I've sold a lot of things.
I've sold door-to-door sales for NPower,
gas and electricity.
I now sell the world's first productivity
drink.
I'm now selling a course for personal
trainers.
The selling component is the bit
that you kind of learn the most about, and
probably the best lesson I can give you
is this.
If 1% of your efforts are successful,
you're doing well.
When you're selling,
think about them more than you.
Give them a guarantee.
Think about what their concerns are.
Build a sales environment that
is more congruent with them being
happy than you being happy. And again,
the stuff that I learned about selling
from
Nutonic,
I'd learnt from selling business
mentorships, and I'd also learned from
selling online coaching.
Once you learn how to sell one thing,
you learn how to
sell all things.
And then there's a scale component.
Now, the scale component
is really the part you guys should be the
most interested
about, because the next three years,
you get the opportunity to do so much
testing
on social media,
so much testing with getting people's
email addresses, and so much
testing with selling,
that your element of scale
is probably going to be what I
said before about a pivot.
If you had said to me back in the day I
was going to be
a three times number one bestselling
author, soon to be four times,
I wouldn't have
believed you. And again, actually,
getting the accolade
that I have for these three
books is really, really difficult.
People that are much better at writing
than me don't have those accolades.
So ask yourself this. Why is it
that a personal trainer that's written a
few
books has got better accolades than most
authors without writing a better book?
Because Will Storr
is a much better author than me.
Much better.
Bestselling author Will Storr.
Doesn't say number one, does it?
I'm only joking.
The reason being is Will Storr
is playing a better authoring game than
me, but I
think that I'm better on social media,
I'm better at email marketing, and I'm
better at creating landing pages.
And although it sounds fucking crazy to
say, this is the reason you should
listen to me, not the fancy car
or anything else, because that is a visual
representation of exactly what I'm saying.
Through becoming a personal trainer,
I managed to learn how to be an author.
Through being a personal trainer
and author,
I could leverage appearances on
television to make my businesses grow
and prosper, and then I can use those
businesses that have grown
and prospered to create the business
mentorship, which
means from the business mentorship,
I now have spare income
that I can allocate
into investing into other businesses
and starting another business in a new
niche
that I have no experience within.
The next three years aren't just
imperative for
you and your coaching business to thrive,
make money, pay your bills, live your
life, enjoy yourselves.
The real opportunity isn't even in the
money that you're
going to make in the next three years.
It is the lessons that you can learn.
So in three years' time, you
are either a business professional firing
on all
cylinders who is an adequate expert in all
of these fields, or you fumbled
the biggest fucking opportunity of your
life to learn the things
necessary for your future.
And you need to really drill this out of
your head.
Chances of you being a successful personal
trainer in 10 years' time
are fucking slim.
About as likely as black cabs and
the College for the Knowledge making a
comeback, which will never happen.
Either you think Blockbuster
is going to make a return
and we're going to go back
to watching fucking tapes,
or you have an opportunity in front of you
to really, really learn a lot.
Because let's come full circle on this.
Although I say that personal training
and online coaching
is a difficult thing to
sell,
it is the fucking biggest gift as a step
into
entrepreneurialism you'll ever get.
As an online personal trainer,
you need no staff, no overheads, no costs.
You need a fucking iPhone, a tripod,
a MacBook, and knowledge of the
gym and training people.
The biggest expense you'd have
is being a qualified PT.
Do you not understand how many businesses
don't even make money in their first
year? So your personal training curse,
and the fact that AI agents
are probably going to fuck you,
is still your biggest blessing,
because as of right
now today,
you have three years where you can grow,
scale, learn,
and become the person you need to so
that if it is three or
six or 10 years' time,
the collapse of personal training as we
know it
comes in, you are either ready or you
are not.
You either did the work or you didn't.
You either learned the lessons
or you didn't. It's that fucking simple.
I teach people all of this for a living.
You can buy the PT course,
link in description.
You can join my business mentorship,
or you can watch this video. It's
that simple.
I didn't mean this to be like a doomsday
video, but if you lot don't get this
right, you're so fucked.